{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Tanya is older than Eric.\nCliff is older than Tanya.\nEric is older than Cliff.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Because the first two statements are true, Eric is the  youngest of the three, so the third statement must be false."}, {"question": "Blueberries cost more than strawberries.\nBlueberries cost less than raspberries.\nRaspberries cost more than strawberries and blueberries.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Because the first two statements are true, raspberries are the most expensive of the three."}, {"question": "All the trees in the park are flowering trees.\nSome of the trees in the park are dogwoods.\nAll dogwoods in the park are flowering trees.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All of the trees in the park are flowering trees, So all dogwoods in the park are flowering trees."}, {"question": "Mara runs faster than Gail.\nLily runs faster than Mara.\nGail runs faster than Lily.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "B", "explanation": "We know from the first two statements that Lily runs fastest. Therefore, the third statement must be false."}, {"question": "Apartments in the Riverdale Manor cost less than apartments in The Gaslight Commons.\nApartments in the Livingston Gate cost more than apartments in the The Gaslight Commons.\nOf the three apartment buildings, the Livingston Gate costs the most.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since the Gaslight Commons costs more than the Riverdale Manor and the Livingston Gate costs more than the Gaslight Commons, it is true that the Livingston Gate costs the most."}, {"question": "The Kingston Mall has more stores than the Galleria.\nThe Four Corners Mall has fewer stores than the Galleria.\nThe Kingston Mall has more stores than the Four Corners Mall.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "A", "explanation": "From the first two statements, you know that the Kingston Mall has the most stores, so the Kingston Mall would have more stores than the Four Corners Mall."}, {"question": "All the tulips in Zoe's garden are white.\nAll the pansies in Zoe's garden are yellow.\nAll the flowers in Zoe's garden are either white or yellow\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The first two statements give information about Zoe's  tulips and pansies. Information about any other kinds of flowers cannot be determined."}, {"question": "During the past year, Josh saw more movies than Stephen.\nStephen saw fewer movies than Darren.\nDarren saw more movies than Josh.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Because the first two sentences are true, both Josh and Darren saw more movies than Stephen. However, it is uncertain as to whether \nDarren saw more movies than Josh."}, {"question": "Rover weighs less than Fido.\nRover weighs more than Boomer.\nOf the three dogs, Boomer weighs the least.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "A", "explanation": "According to the first two statements, Fido weighs  the most and Boomer weighs the least."}, {"question": "All the offices on the 9th floor have wall-to-wall carpeting.\nNo wall-to-wall carpeting is pink.\nNone of the offices on the 9th floor has pink wall-to-wall carpeting.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "A", "explanation": "If no wall-to-wall carpeting is pink and all the offices have wall-to-wall carpeting, none of the offices has pink wall-to-wall carpeting."}, {"question": "Class A has a higher enrollment than Class B.\nClass C has a lower enrollment than Class B.\nClass A has a lower enrollment than Class C.\nIf the first two statements are true, the third statement is", "opta": "true", "optb": "false", "ans": "B", "explanation": "From the first two statements, we know that of the three classes, Class A has the highest enrollment, so the third statement must be false."}]]}